练习 6-2：比较 L 与 T、D、N 的声音。跟我读，先纵向读，
Exercise 6-2, sounds comparing L with T, D, and N. Repeat after me, first down and
再横向读。第一，在词首。La、lo、li、na、no、ni、ta、to、ti，
then across. One, at the beginning of a word. La, lo, li, na, no, ni, ta, to, ti,
da, do, di, la, na, ta, da, lo, no, to, do, li, ni, ti, di. Two, in the middle of a
word, belly, collar, Alley, Benny, Connor, Annie, Betty, Cotter, at ease, Belly,
Benny, Betty, Collar, Connor, cotter alley, Annie, at ease three at the end of a word
a hole hold hone hoed call called, con, cod, be, fill, full, fool, fail, fell,
feel、fuel、furl。现在看 3B 组；这个练习有三个功能。
feel, fuel, furl. Look at the group 3B. This exercise has three functions. 1.
第一，练习词尾 L。第二，复习元音。第三，用阶梯方式复习这些相同的词。
Practice final L's. 2. Review vowel sounds. 3. Review the same words with the
注意。每个词在 L 后都有一个很轻的 schwa。这是为了
staircase. Note. Notice that each word has a tiny schwa after the L. This is to
这样可以让舌头到位，并让单词收尾完整。
encourage your tongue to be in the right position to give your words a finished
请夸张词尾 L，以及那个本来听不见的 schwa。接下来重复最后一组词。
sound. Exaggerate the final L and its otherwise inaudible schwa. Repeat the last
group of words. Fill, full, fool, fail, fell, feel, fuel, furl. Once you're
舌头习惯这个位置后，就让它自然停在那里。
comfortable with your tongue in this position, let it just languish there while
继续发声；这就是母语者的做法。再读一遍。
you continue vocalizing, which is what a native speaker does. Repeat again. fill,
full, fool, fail, feel, fuel, furl